(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ホロライブ4期生 5周年記念！
Hololive 4th Gen 5th Anniversary!
公式メンバーシップ 限定壁紙・限定絵文字
Official Membership Limited Wallpapers & Emotes
限定絵文字
対応プラン：プラスプラン/プレミアムプラン/デラックスプラン
Limited Emotes
Supported Plans: Plus / Premium / Deluxe
限定壁紙
対応プラン：プレミアムプラン/デラックスプラン
Limited Wallpaper
Supported Plans: Premium / Deluxe
U-M-R! U-M-R! UMA じゃないよ うまる!
U-M-R! U-M-R! Not a UMA, it's Umaru!
はんてんしんてい うれいや遊び倒せ!
Flip it over, forget your worries, and play 'til you drop!
もっと もっと 楽しめよ乙女
Enjoy even more, young maiden
みんなに気づかれないように
So that no one notices
いざゆけひもうとライフ!
Go forth, dry-sister life!
お気に入りのフードかぶり
Putting on my favorite hood
今日も今日とてゴロゴロして
Rolling around today just like always
大好物のポテチを手に
With my favorite potato chips in hand
パソコンとにらめっこしちゃえ
Having a staring contest with the computer
立てば芍薬 座れば牡丹
Standing like a peony, sitting like a tree peony
歩く姿は百合の花
Walking like a lily flower
誰もが羨む完璧JK
A perfect high school girl everyone envies
ほら玄関くぐったら変身だ
Look, once I cross the threshold, it's a transformation
さあぐーたらに極楽!
Now, it's lazy paradise!
いつだって 食う・寝る・遊ぶの三連コンボ
Always the three-combo of eat, sleep, and play
ずっと ずっと ゲームは友達
Forever and ever, games are my friends
お兄ちゃんは厳しいけど
Big brother is strict, but
きっと きっと 許してくれちゃうの
I'm sure, I'm sure he'll forgive me
わがまま放題は
Being as selfish as I want
大好きの裏返し!
Is just another side of my love!
U-M-R! U-M-R! UMA じゃないよ うまる!
U-M-R! U-M-R! Not a UMA, it's Umaru!
外では猫かぶり
Outside, I'm a goody-goody
今日も明日も演じるのです
I'll keep acting today and tomorrow
大好評の笑顔を武器に
With my highly acclaimed smile as my weapon
友達にバレないように
So my friends won't find out
立てば二等身 座ればまん丸
Standing at two heads tall, sitting like a perfect circle
歩く姿はちんちくりん
Walking like a little runt
誰でも
Anyone...
声も癒せる愛嬌マシマシ
With an extra dose of voice-soothing charm
さあ 限界突破 甘いもん食いたいじゃん
Come on, break the limits, don't you want to eat something sweet?
宴の始まりだー！
Let the feast begin!
いよいよ いよいよ 行っちゃおうか！
Finally, finally, let's go for it!
甘えで初心な女の子
Spoiled and innocent girl...
演じてみても
...even if I try to act like one,
お兄ちゃんだけは騙せない
I can't fool you, Onii-chan.
嫌われたくないもん
Because I don't want you to hate me.
素直に言えない「ありがとう」
The 'thank you' I can't say honestly,
態度で示そう
I'll show it through my attitude.
さあ 限界突破 甘いもん食いたいじゃん
Come on, break the limits, I want to eat something sweet!
お兄ちゃんなんて知らない
I don't care about Onii-chan!
なーんつって
Just kidding!
一心同体 二人でひとつ
Two bodies, one soul, two as one,
それが兄弟でしょ
that's what siblings are, right?
一蓮托生 二人きりの
Sharing the same fate, just the two of us,
運命共同体
a shared destiny.
自由奔放 笑い飛ばせ
Free-spirited, laugh it all off,
もっともっと 楽しんだもん勝ち
more and more, the one who enjoys it wins!
天真爛漫 スマイルで
With an innocent smile,
ギュッギュッと心を掴んじゃうの
I'll grab your heart tight!
やりたい放題は
Doing whatever I want is
信頼の裏返し
proof of our trust.
U.M.R! U.M.R!
UMAじゃないよ うまる！
It's not UMA, it's Umaru!
U.M.R! U.M.R!
UMAじゃないよ うまる！ Yeah!
It's not UMA, it's Umaru! Yeah!
はい おしまい！
Okay, that's all!
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for a future that won't stop,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
holding tight to an unyielding wish.
ゆずれない願い
作詞：田村直美　作曲：田村直美／石川寛門
Yuzurenai Negai
Lyrics: Naomi Tamura Composition: Naomi Tamura / Hiroto Ishikawa
海の色が赤く染まってゆく
The color of the sea is being dyed red,
無重力状態
a state of zero gravity.
このまま風にさらわれたい
I want to be swept away by the wind just like this.
いつも飛べないハードルを
The hurdles I could never fly over,
負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
I've cleared them with a spirit that won't lose, but...
出し切れない実力は
The ability I can't quite bring out fully,
誰のせい？
whose fault is it?
止まらない未来を目指して
Aiming for a future that won't stop,
ゆずれない願いを抱きしめて
holding tight to an unyielding wish.
色あせない心の地図
A map of the heart that won't fade,
光にかざそう
I'll hold it up to the light.
どれだけ泣けば朝に出会えるの
How much must I cry before I meet the morning?
孤独な夜
In the lonely night,
初めて限界を感じた日
the day I felt my limits for the first time.
きっと恋に落ちるのは
Falling in love must be
まばたきみたいな一瞬の情熱だけど
an instantaneous passion, like a blink, but...
愛し続く坂道で
on the slope of continuing love,
強さ覚えたい
I want to learn strength.
止まらない未来を夢見て
Dreaming of a future that won't stop,
口を閉じ瞳を輝かせてきたけれど
I've kept my mouth shut and eyes shining, but...
もっと大きな優しさが見えた
I saw an even greater kindness.
飛べないハードルを
負けない気持ちでクリアしてきたけど
The hurdles I couldn't fly over,
I've cleared them with a spirit that won't lose, but...
スタートラインに立つたびに 怯えていた
Every time I stood at the start line, I was frightened.
止まらない未来を描いて
Painting a future that won't stop,
腕を伸ばし
stretching out my arms.
ゆずれない願い
Unyielding Wish
...開いて
...open up
止まらない
unstoppable
未来を目指して
aiming for the future
ゆずれない願いを
clasping my unyielding wish
抱きしめて
tightly to me
色褪せない
unfading
心の地図
map of the heart
光にかざそう
let's hold it up to the light
他の誰かになんて
I can't become
なれやしないよ そんなの分かってるんだ
anyone else, I know that
明日を信じてみたいの
I want to try believing in tomorrow
かすかな自分を 愛せなかったとしても
even if I couldn't love my faint self
Teenager Forever
望んだこと全てが
Not everything I wished for
叶うわけはないよ そんなの分かってるんだ
will come true, I know that
深い傷もいずれは
Will even deep wounds eventually
かさぶたに変わって 剥がれ落ちるだろうか
turn into scabs and peel away?
いつまでも相変わらず つまらない話を
Always the same as ever, looking for happiness
つまらないの中に どこまでも幸せを探すよ
within boring stories, no matter where
伝えたい思いは溢れてるのに
Though the feelings I want to convey are overflowing,
伝え方が分からなくて
I don't know how to do it,
今でも言葉を探してるんだ
so I'm still searching for words even now
遠く知っていた夢の欠片に
Notice the fragments of dreams I knew from afar
毒めく貴方の煌めきに 気づけたらいいんだ
and notice your toxic sparkle
結局のところ誰も
In the end, no one will tell me
教えてはくれないんだ 進むべき道なんて
the path I should take
等身大のままで
I'll live life as I am,
生きていくぜ 年を重ねても
even as I get older
いつまでも相変わらず つまらない話を
Always the same as ever, looking for happiness
つまらないの中に どこまでも幸せを探すよ
within boring stories, no matter where
煌めきを探せよ
Search for the sparkle
散々振り回して 振り回されて
Tossing and being tossed around,
大事なものは貴方だって
never realizing that you
ことに気づけないままで
are what's most important
一体未来はどうなるのかなんてことより
Rather than what the future will hold,
毒めく今の煌めきに
I hope I can notice the toxic
気づけたらいいんだ
sparkle of the present
他の誰かになんて
I can't become
なれやしないよ そんなの分かってるんだ
anyone else, I know that
明日を信じてみたいの
I want to try believing in tomorrow
かすかな自分を 愛せなかったとしても
even if I couldn't love my faint self
ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星
Guitar and Solitude and Blue Planet
突然降る夕立
A sudden evening shower,
ああ 傘もないや いや
ah, I don't even have an umbrella, no, no
空のご機嫌なんか知らない
I don't care about the sky's mood
季節の変わり目
What should I wear
の服は何着りゃいいんだろ
during the change of seasons?
ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星 / 歌：常闇トワ
Guitar, Solitude, and the Blue Planet / Vocals: Tokoyami Towa
季節の変わり目の服は
The clothes for the change of seasons
何着りゃいいんだろ
What should I wear?
春と秋
Spring and autumn
どこいっちゃったんだよ
Where did they go?
息も出来ない　情報の圧力
Can't even breathe, the pressure of information
めまいの螺旋だ　わたしはどこにいる
A spiral of dizziness, where am I?
こんなに　こんなに　息の音がするのに
Even though I can hear my own breathing so clearly
変だね　世界の音がしない
It's strange, I can't hear the sounds of the world
足りない　足りない　誰にも気づかれない
Not enough, not enough, no one notices me
殴り書きみたいな音　出せない状態で叫んだよ
Screaming in a state where I can't make a sound like a scribble
「ありのまま」なんて誰に見せるんだ
Who would I show "my true self" to?
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
Stupid me, I just sing
ぶちまけちゃおうか　星に
Shall I pour it all out to the stars?
エリクサーに張り替える作業も　なんとなくなんだ
The task of changing to Elixir strings is just kind of whatever
欠けた爪を少し触る
I touch my chipped fingernail a bit
半径300mmの体で必死に鳴いてる
Desperately crying out with a body of 300mm radius
音楽にとってココが地球だな
For music, this is Earth
空気を握って　空を殴るよ
I grip the air and punch the sky
何にも起きない　わたしは無力さ
Nothing happens, I'm powerless
だけどさ　その手で　この鉄を弾いたら
But if I pluck these steel strings with those hands
何かが変わって見えたような
It felt like something changed
眩しい　眩しい　そんなに光るなよ
Dazzling, dazzling, don't shine so brightly
わたしのダサい影がより色濃くなってしまうだろ
My uncool shadow will only become more distinct
なんでこんなに熱くなっちゃって止まんない
Why did it get so hot and won't stop?
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
Stupid me, I just sing
うるさいんだって心臓
My heart is so loud
蒼い惑星　ひとりぼっち　いっぱいの音を聞いてきた
Blue planet, all alone, I've heard so many sounds
回り続けて幾億年　一瞬でもいいから...
Revolving for billions of years, even for a moment...
ああ　聴いて　聴けよ
Ah, listen, listen to me!
わたし　わたし　わたしはここにいる
I, I, I am right here
殴り書きみたいな音　出せない状態で叫んだよ
Screaming in a state where I can't make a sound like a scribble
なりたい　なりたい　何者かでいい
I want to be, I want to be, someone, anyone
馬鹿なわたしは歌うだけ
Stupid me, I just sing
ぶちまけちゃおうか　星に
Shall I pour it all out to the stars?
とおい　とおい　むかしばなし
A long, long time ago story
それはきっと　あすのはなし
That is surely a story of tomorrow
片羽 / 歌：天音かなた
One Wing / Vocals: Amane Kanata
“もう　飛べやしないさ”
"I can't fly anymore"
落ち続ける夜から醒めた
I woke up from the night of continuous falling
白い部屋の片隅で
In a corner of a white room
彷徨ってる　自由をなくして
Wandering around, having lost my freedom
塞ぐ　倒れ込んだまま
Shutting myself in, having collapsed
ああ　細い片翼が
Ah, a thin single wing...
ああ　ないんだ
Ah, ...is gone
叫んだ　心が止まらなくて
I screamed, my heart wouldn't stop
機械みたいに　きしむ僕を　現実が嗤った
Reality sneered at me as I creaked like a machine
その時　誰かが囁いたんだ
At that moment, someone whispered
「あなたに　あげた　つばさ」
"The wings I gave you"
“The wings I gave to you”
「わたしの　ゆめみた　せかい」
“The world that I dreamed of”
羽ばたきたい
I want to spread my wings
大空へ
Into the vast sky
嗚呼 風鳴く
Ah, the wind wails
止まらないで 高く高く
Don't stop, higher and higher
幾度夢みた 祈った 雲の果て
How many times I've dreamed and prayed, beyond the clouds
終わりを越えて 高く高く
Beyond the end, higher and higher
かけがえのない ガラクタの羽で
With these irreplaceable, junk-like wings
“星を見失った”
“I've lost sight of the stars”
紛れ住む 人間のセカイ
Living hidden in the human world
一つの羽じゃ飛べない
I can't fly with just one wing
もう飛びたくない
I don't want to fly anymore
色彩の 半分だけで
With only half of the colors
底を這うこともできなかった
I couldn't even crawl along the bottom
「わたしには もう いらないの」
“I don't need it anymore”
かわりに ひかりは きみがみてよ
Instead, you look at the light
苛立つほどに 青かった エデンで泣いてた
Crying in Eden, which was so blue it was irritating
その時 掴んでくれた 誰かの手
That's when someone's hand grabbed mine
嗚呼
Ah
あなたがくれた 希望で
With the hope you gave me
約束の羽で今
With the promised wings, now
飛ぶなくちゃ
I have to fly
共に往く
Let's go together
地平の先へ
Beyond the horizon
壊れるまで 高く高く
Until I break, higher and higher
今の僕は 片羽でいい
I'm fine with being single-winged for now
飛べるよ 信じて
I can fly, believe me
飛べるよ その先へ
I can fly, towards the future
飛べるよ 楽園
I can fly, to paradise
永遠の彼方まで
To the far reaches of eternity
嗚呼
Ah
遥か 彼方まで
Far, far away
君をのせて
Carrying You
あの地平線
That horizon
輝くのは
Shining
どこかに君を かくしているから
Is because you're hidden somewhere
たくさんの灯が
The many lights
なつかしいのは
Make me feel nostalgic
あのどれかひとつに 君がいるから
Because you are in one of them
さあ でかけよう
Now, let's set out
ひときれのパン
A piece of bread
ナイフ、ランプ、かばんに つめこんで
Knife, lamp, packed in a bag
父さんが残した 熱い想い
The burning passion Father left behind
母さんがくれた あのまなざし
The gaze Mother gave me
地球はまわる
The Earth turns
君をかくして
Hiding you
輝く瞳
Shining eyes
きらめく灯
Sparkling lights
地球はまわる
The Earth turns
君をのせて
Carrying you
いつかきっと出会う
One day we'll surely meet
ぼくらをのせて
Carrying us
父さんが残した 熱い想い
Father's burning desire he left behind
母さんがくれた あのまなざし
Mother's look she gave me
地球はまわる 君をかくして
The Earth rotates, hiding you
輝く瞳 きらめく灯火
Shining eyes, sparkling lights
地球はまわる 君をのせて
The Earth rotates, carrying you
いつかきっと出会う ぼくらをのせて
Someday we will surely meet, carrying us
どうざんなのあ〜！
How was that, nanora!
ルーナの歌、めちゃめちゃ聞き入っちゃったよ！
Luna, I was totally captivated by your singing!
いや、かなたんの歌もかっこよかったのらよ。
No, Kanatan's singing was cool too, nanora.
本当？ あ、じゃあそんな社交辞令も終わったところで。
Really? Well, now that the social niceties are over...
お〜？
Oh?
というわけで、4期生ライブ皆さん楽しんでますかー？
So, is everyone enjoying the 4th generation live?
イエーイ！
Yay!
ハッシュタグはこちら。
The hashtag is right here.
ハッシュタグ、これで！
This is the hashtag!
ガンガン呟いてな〜！
Keep those tweets coming!
つぶやいてのら！
Please tweet about it!
はい、そしてこのステージ見てください。めちゃめちゃ綺麗だよね。
Yes, and look at this stage. It's so beautiful, isn't it?
綺麗！
Beautiful!
これね、時間が進むと景色も変わっていくステージでございます。
This is a stage where the scenery changes as time passes.
しゅごいのら〜。
That's amazing, nanora~.
ぜひチェックしてください。
Please check it out.
さてさて、お次の曲なんですが、ルーナさん。
Now then, for the next song... Luna-san.
ご準備の方はいかがでしょうか？
How are your preparations coming along?
まあ、任せのら。
Well, leave it to me, nanora.
おお。
Oh.
では、次の曲は擦り散らかした「Get Wild」。
Well then, the next song is the well-worn "Get Wild".
Get Wild.
アスファルトタイヤを切りつけながら
Tearing up the asphalt tires
暗闇走り抜ける
Running through the darkness
チープなスリルに身をまかせても
Even if I give myself up to cheap thrills
明日に怯えていたよ
I was afraid of tomorrow
It's your pain or my pain or somebody's pain
誰かのために生きられるなら
If I can live for someone else
It's your dream or my dream or somebody's dream
何も怖くはない
I'm not afraid of anything
Get wild and tough
ひとりでは解けない愛のパズルを抱いて
Holding the puzzle of love that cannot be solved alone
Get wild and tough
この街でやさしさに甘えていたくはない
I don't want to rely on the kindness in this city
Get chance and luck
君だけが守れるものがどこかにあるさ
There is something that only you can protect somewhere
Get chance and luck
ひとりでも傷ついた夢をとりもどすよ
Even alone, I'll take back my wounded dream
クルマのライトにキスを投げては
Throwing a kiss at the car's headlights
シャドウで踊るあの娘
That girl dancing in the shadow
冷たい夜空をステージにして
Making the cold night sky the stage
哀しくおどけていたね
You were joking around sadly
It's your pain or my pain or somebody's pain
誰かのために愛せるのなら
If I can love for someone else
It's your dream or my dream or somebody's dream
きっと強くなれる
I can surely become stronger
Get wild and tough
ひとりでは消せない痛み心に抱いて
Holding the pain in my heart that cannot be erased alone
Get wild and tough
この街で自由をもてあましだくはない
I don't want to have more freedom than I can handle in this city
Get chance and luck
君だけが守れるものがどこかにあるさ
There is something that only you can protect somewhere
見つけだしたなら
If I find it...
Get wild and tough
一人でも
Even alone
傷ついた夢を取りもどすよ
I'll take back the wounded dream
Get wild and tough
一人でも
Even alone
解けない愛のパズルを抱いて
Holding the unsolvable puzzle of love
Get wild and tough
この街で
In this city
やさしさに甘えていたくはない
I don't want to rely on kindness
Get chance and luck
君だけが
Only you
守れるものがどこかにあるさ
There is something only you can protect somewhere
Get wild and tough
一人でも
Even alone
傷ついた夢を取りもどすよ
I'll take back the wounded dream
Get wild and tough
Our step
いつだってそう「僕なんて」さって
Always like that, saying things like "someone like me"
うつむいてばかりのMAYDAY
A MAYDAY where I'm always looking down
つまずいて泣いて「どうせ」って口癖が
Stumbling, crying, the habit of saying "anyway"
染みついてさ
Is stained into me
いつからかまた積もる焦り
The impatience that has piled up again since when
でも胸の奥にある光
But the light deep in my chest
繋ぐ点と線の先へ
Beyond the points and lines connected
踏み出すイメージの先へ
Beyond the image of stepping forward
遠くたっていい
It's okay if it's far
ほら虹をまたいで
Look, cross the rainbow
さあ心のままに音を奏でる
Now, play the sound as your heart desires
逸る鼓動は今を刻む証だ
The rushes of heartbeat are proof of carving the present
響け僕らの想いを乗せて
Resonate, carrying our feelings
高く遠く歌を紡いで
Spinning a song high and far
Lalala...
季節巡って駆け抜けて
Seasons go around, running through
気づけば大人になって
Before I knew it, I've become an adult
幼い日の心は胸の奥くすぶってた
The heart of my childhood was smoldering deep in my chest
怖いことも増えたけど
Fearful things have increased too
でも今だから見える世界
But the world I can see because it's now
今だから信じてる世界
The world I believe in because it's now
儚さの中に確かに灯る光
The light that certainly lights up in the fleetingness
繋いでいこう
Let's connect it
さあ新しいステージへ
Now, to a new stage
心の中の音を聴かせて
Let me hear the sound in your heart
大袈裟だっていいありのままの自分で
It's okay even if it's an exaggeration, as your true self
咲き誇れもっといつまでもずっと
Blooming more, forever and always
歌いながら日々を紡いで
Spinning the days while singing
うつむいて泣いた日もあったけど
There were days when I looked down and cried, but
涙も力になる
Tears also become strength
刻めHEART
Carve the HEART
鳴らせBEAT
Sound the BEAT
響け僕らのメロディ
Resonate, our melody
ねえあの日の夢も
Hey, the dream of that day
今の自分も
and my current self
描く未来も全て抱きしめるよ
The future I draw, I'll embrace it all
さあ旅を続けよう
Now, let's continue the journey
どこまでもずっと
wherever and forever
手を繋いで
Holding hands
ほら僕らの一歩だ
look, it's our step
心のままに音を奏でる
Play the sound as your heart desires
逸る鼓動は...
The rushing heartbeat...
今を刻む証が
The proof of living this moment
響け僕らの想いも乗せて
Resonate, carrying our feelings too
高く遠く歌を紡いで
Spinning a song high and far
Lalala
Overdose
本当は分かっていた いけないことだったって
I actually knew it, that it was something I shouldn't do
分かっていたのに この手をすり抜ける全部が愛に見えたの
I knew it, but everything slipping through these hands
looked like love
確かめていた言葉が形になって揺れるだけ yeah
The words I was confirming
just take shape and sway, yeah
弾いて帰ってきたそれだけ つまらないな
It just bounced back and came back, how boring
世界の闇合わせ あとちょっとで分かりかけてたのに
The world's darkness aligning,
I was just about to understand
飲んで吐いて 全部忘れちゃえ 水をまとった脳神経
Drink, vomit, forget it all
Cranial nerves covered in water
鏡合わせ 見つめ合えたら
Mirror image, if only we could look at each other
Overdose 君とふたり やるせない日々
Overdose, just the two of us, these helpless days
解像度の悪い夢を見たい
I want to see a low-resolution dream
Overdose 君とふたり 甘いハッタリ
Overdose, just the two of us, a sweet bluff
Don't stop the music, darling
本当に分かっていた いけないことだったって
I really knew it, that it was something I shouldn't do
分かってる 多分 時間だけが過ぎていく 問答で満ちていく
I know. Probably just time passing,
filling up with questions and answers
言い訳する間もなく 裸になってしまうだけ yeah
Without even a moment to make excuses,
I just end up naked, yeah
きっと溜まっていくんだずっと 終わってしまえばいいと ふと
It'll surely keep piling up forever,
suddenly thinking it should just end
傷んで腐っていくあの生果実のように僕ら壊れていく
Like that raw fruit that spoils and rots,
we're breaking down
踊って狂って全部忘れちゃえ
Dance, go crazy, forget it all
嘘を被った仲良しと隣り合わせ 見つめ合えたら
Side by side with friends wearing lies,
if only we could look at each other
Overdose 君とふたり 分かり合いたいのにお互い
Overdose, just the two of us,
even though we want to understand each other
分が悪い嘘が嫌い
I hate the disadvantageous lies
Overdose 君とふたり 分かり合いたいのにお互い
Overdose, just the two of us,
even though we want to understand each other
Don't stop the music, darling
Overdose 君とふたり やるせない日々
Overdose, just the two of us, these helpless days
解像度の悪い夢を見たい
I want to see a low-resolution dream
Overdose 君とふたり 甘いハッタリ
Overdose, just the two of us, a sweet bluff
Don't stop the music, darling
Overdose 君とふたり 分からないけどお互い
Overdose, just the two of us,
I don't know but we both...
分が悪い嘘でもいい
Even if it's a disadvantageous lie, it's fine
Overdose 君とふたり 甘いハッタリ
Overdose, just the two of us, a sweet bluff
Don't stop the music, darling
はーい！ということでー！
Hi! So...!
いえーい！
Yay!
MCいきたいと思います！
Let's start the MC!
じゃあ1人じゃ寂しいので、
Well, since it's lonely alone...
ほい！
Hoi!
おいで、おいで。
Come here, come here.
いえーい！
Yay!
ぺこっと！またわためーとね、MCをやっていきたいと思います。
Pekotto! I'm going to do the MC with Watame again.
はい、かっこよかったねー！
Yes, that was cool!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ということで、じゃあお互いのね、あの、歌った曲について触れていきましょうか。
So, let's talk about the songs we both sang.
はい！何歌ったんですか？
Yes! What did you sing?
はい、トワは『ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星』と、『Overdose』を歌わせていただきました！
Yes, Towa sang "Guitar, Loneliness and Blue Planet"
and "Overdose"!
歌ったたったたったた！
Sang-sang-sang-sang-sang!
やめて、ねえ。
Stop it, hey.
かっこよかった！
That was cool!
かっこよかったよ、でも、その「歌ったたったた」感が。
It was cool, but that "sang-sang-sang" feel...
はい、でね、その『Overdose』は流行りの曲、たたた、ちょっと歌ってみて、
Yes, and "Overdose" is a popular song,
I tried singing it,
あと一曲悩んだんですけど、それはなんかマネちゃんが、トワさんに合うよって言って選んでくれた曲が『ギターと孤独と蒼い惑星』で、今回歌わせていただきました！
and I was undecided about the other song,
but my manager chose "Guitar, Loneliness and Blue Planet"
saying it would suit Towa, so I sang it this time!
そうなんだ。
I see.
何てったの？ ありがとう。
What did you say? Thank you.
確かに。トワも歌いやすかった。
Indeed. It was easy for Towa to sing too.
ああー、イエーイ。
Oh, yeah!
迷彩ハイ！
Meisai Hai!
ありがとう。んで、わためが…
Thank you. And, Watame...
わためは「イネンジャForever」と「あわすてっぷ」を歌わせていただきました。
Watame performed "Inenja Forever" and "Awasu Step".
おおー！「あわすてっぷ」めっちゃよかった！
Oh! "Awasu Step" was so good!
嬉しい。これが新曲なんだけど…
I'm glad. This is a new song, but...
今までの、私が出した楽曲の歌詞が入ってたり…
...it contains lyrics from songs I've released so far...
曲名が入ってたり…
...or song titles...
する、この周年にぴったりの曲になってるんですよ。
...making it a perfect song for this anniversary.
いや、そうなんだよ。トワもリハーサルで聴いてて、「すごいエモい曲、いい曲だね」って言ったら…
Yeah, that's right. Towa heard it in rehearsal and said, "It's a very emotional and good song," and then...
歌詞とかね、曲名が入ってるっていうのを教えてもらったんで、先にちょっと味わっちゃいました。
...I was told that lyrics and song titles were in it, so I already enjoyed it a bit beforehand.
でも！
But!
皆、待ってるんですよ、これ。
Everyone is waiting for this.
え？何ですか？
Eh? What is it?
この後…
After this...
何？
What?
この「あわすてっぷ」のMVが…
...this "Awasu Step" MV...
何？
What?
わためチャンネルで投稿されます！
...will be posted on Watame Channel!
なーにー！？
Whaaat!?
反応いいな！
Good reaction!
気持ちええー。
Feels good.
ありがてぇ、ありがてぇ。ぜひ見てください。
Thank you, thank you. Please check it out.
見てねー！
Watch it!
はい、そしてそして…
Yes, and and...
なんと！ジャジャーン！
...and! Tada!
ライブ衣装！
Live outfits!
お互い並ぶの初めてだよね。初めてだね。
It's the first time we line up like this. First time, right?
ちょっとシナジーがあったり、このヒラヒラとか。
There's some synergy, like these frills.
確かにね。
True.
ちょっとスクショタイムするか。
Let's do some screenshot time.
しようよ。あ、ここにいてね。
Let's. Ah, stay here.
イエーイ。
Yay.
羊ピース？
Hitsuji Peace?
イエーイ。
Yay.
羊ピース！ハート？
Hitsuji Peace! Heart?
あ、もうやってるし。
Oh, you're already doing it.
イエーイ。
Yay.
まぁ, 撮れたところで。
Well, now that we've taken them.
えー、そうですよ。我々、なんと今日で…
Yes, so. As of today, we...
5周年！
5th anniversary!
5周年か、早いなぁ。
5th anniversary... it's fast.
いや、もう5周年なんて言ったら我々もね、お局さんですから。
Well, 5 years means we are already senior ladies.
お局？
Senior ladies?
お局さんです。
Senior ladies.
5年で？
In 5 years?
お姉さん？
Older sisters?
5年ですよ。
5 years.
後輩いっぱい入ってきたでしょ。
Many juniors have come in, right?
確かにね。もう中堅ぐらいになっちゃったよ。
True. We've become like middle management.
ちょっと、もうおばさんです。
We're already old ladies.
おいおいおい！
Hey, hey, hey!
まだまだですよ。
Not yet.
まだ？
Still?
まだまだ。じゃあ、ちなみに。
Not yet. By the way...
6年目に入るわけですよ。
...we're entering our 6th year.
6年目の目標、聞いていいですか？
Can I ask your goal for the 6th year?
まだまだね、ピッチピチに。
Well, staying perfectly fresh.
若い子には負けんぞっていう気持ちで頑張っていきたいと思っとります。
I want to keep working hard with a feeling of not losing to the young ones.
おばさんやないか！
You're an old lady!
もう負けてるやないか。「ピッチピチ」って言ってる時点で。
You're already losing! Just by saying "fresh".
自分がピッチピチじゃないって言ってるやないか。
You're admitting you're not fresh yourself.
ピッチピチだよ！
I'm fresh!
まぁ、そうだね。そんなトワっちは何かあるの？
Well, true. What about you, Towa-chi?
そうですね、6年目は…
Well, for the 6th year...
健康に暮らしたいですね。
...I want to live healthily.
ババアやないか！
You're a grandma!
苦しいー！苦しいー！
That hurts! That hurts!
ババアは言い過ぎた、ごめん。
Grandma was too much, sorry.
いや、まぁ、大丈夫ですよ。全然傷ついてないですから。
No, it's fine. I'm not hurt at all.
そうだね。言い慣れてるから。
Right. Because I'm used to it.
おい！
Hey!
捲（まく）ってるぞ、お前。
You're hitting back!
すみません、ループしてますよ、皆さん。ループしてますよ。
Sorry, everyone, we're in a loop. We're looping.
お祝いの場だよ。
It's a celebration!
もうこんな、もう次の曲行けなくなっちゃうじゃん。
We can't move to the next song like this.
一緒に歌うんだよ。まだ終わってないよ。
We're singing together. It's not over yet.
そうだよね。
True.
じゃあ、ちょっと次の曲。落ち着かせて、行きたいと思います。
Well, let's calm down and go to the next song.
落ち着かせて。はい。
Calm down. Yes.
じゃあ、一緒にタイトルコールしてね。
Then, do the title call with me.
はい。
Yes.
では、聴いてください。「メリーゴーランド」。
Well then, please listen to "Merry-Go-Round".
メリーゴーランド 作詞・作曲：優里
Merry-Go-Round Lyrics/Composition: Yuuri
好きになるってどんなこと
What does it mean to fall in love?
新しい自分に会うこと
It's meeting a new version of yourself
好きと口にできなかったこと
The things I couldn't say I liked
あなたの幸せの中
In the midst of your happiness
私がいなかったこと
The fact that I wasn't there
それを受け入れてしまったこと
The fact that I accepted that
一人泣いてたバスタブの中
In the bathtub where I cried alone
顔が痛くて あなたに会いたくて
My face hurt, I wanted to see you
愛してるって何回
How many times did I say "I love you"?
私口にしたのだろう
How many times did I utter those words?
なのにどうして 今そばに
Yet why, right now, by my side...
誰もいないの
...is there no one there?
愛してるって何回
How many times did I hear "I love you"?
私耳にしたのなら
If I had only heard those words
寂しさだけが この胸に
Only loneliness, in this chest...
残っているのです
...is what remains
好きになるってどんなこと
What does it mean to fall in love?
...一人泣いていたら
...if I were crying alone,
そばにいないといけないと思うこと
I'd think that I have to be by your side.
一人泣いた　ベッドの中
Crying alone in bed.
声も顔も　心も愛せない
I can't love your voice, your face, or your heart.
違う場所に生まれてたのなら
If I had been born in a different place...
違う私だったのかな
...would I have been a different person?
生まれ変われるのなら
If I could be reborn,
一人じゃなくなるかな
would I not be alone anymore?
会いに行くってもう何度
How many times have I said,
私口にしたのだろう
'I'll go to see you'?
なのにどうして今そばに
Then why is there no one
誰もいないの
by my side right now?
会いに来てってもう何度
How many times have I heard you say,
私耳にしたのだろう
'Come and see me'?
後悔だけがこの胸に
Only regret remains
残ってるのです
in my heart.
もしもあの日あの瞬間に
If at that moment on that day,
わがままを口にできたら
I could have spoken my selfish wish...
思い切り泣いて　その胸に
Crying my eyes out, in your arms,
また会える
we could meet again.
We can meet again...
どんなに追いかけても
No matter how much I chase it,
追いつかないメリーゴーランド
this merry-go-round I can't catch up to.
愛するってほら
Look, loving someone
こんなに苦しいのです
is so painful.
それすらも愛して
Loving even that,
生きていくと思えるほど
to the point where I think I can live on...
あなたのことを心から
...I'm thinking of you
思っているのです
from the bottom of my heart.
ルルルルル...
Lu lu lu lu lu...
ロキ
作詞・作曲：みきとP
Roki
Composition/Lyrics: mikitoP
さあ　日進月歩　昼夜逆転　VOCALOID 30ワット
Well, steady progress, day and night reversal, Vocaloid 30 watts.
テレキャスター背負ったサブカルボーイがバンド仲間にゃハッタリを
A subculture boy with a Telecaster on his back, bluffing to his bandmates.
湯冷めしちゃって　お嬢ちゃん
You've got a chill, little girl.
お金も才能もなまじあるだけ厄介です
Having money and talent half-heartedly just makes things troublesome.
Boys be ambitious　(はいはい)
Boys be ambitious (Yeah, yeah)
Like this old man
長い前髪　君誰の信者
Long bangs, whose follower are you?
信者...
Follower...
勘違いすんな　教祖はお前だ
Don't get it twisted, the cult leader is you.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki, Roki, rock 'n' rock 'n' roll!
かき鳴らすエレクトリックギターは
Strumming that electric guitar...
Don't Stop! Don't Stop!
さあ　君のすべてを
Now, show me
曝け出してみせろよ
everything you've got!
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki, Roki, rock 'n' rock 'n' roll!
さあ　日進月歩　一曲書いてる
Well, steady progress, writing a song,
フォロワー増えてる
followers are increasing.
でもあの頃の人気はそんなにないから
But your popularity isn't what it used to be,
色々大変ですね
so it's pretty tough, isn't it?
はっきり言うな　匿名愛好
Don't say it so bluntly, lover of anonymity.
はっきり見せない　実写のアイコン
Refusing to show your real-life face in your icon.
愛おしいほど　自意識過剰ボーイ
So endearing, you self-conscious boy.
ぶっちゃけ　どんだけ　賢く
To be honest, no matter how clever
あざとく　やったって
or calculating you are,
10年後にメイクは落ちてんだよ
in 10 years, the makeup will have worn off.
Boys be ambitious　(はいはい)
Boys be ambitious (Yeah, yeah)
Like this old man
生き抜くためだ　決めろ Selfy
It's to survive, strike a pose for the selfie.
Selfy...
Selfie...
死ぬんじゃねえぞ　お互いにな
Don't you go and die now, for both our sakes.
ロキロキのロックンロックンロール
Roki, Roki, rock 'n' rock 'n' roll!
吹っ切れない　怠惰でもいい
It's okay to be lazy and unable to get over it.
ダンスダンス！
Dance, dance!
さぁ目の前のあの子を
Now, that girl in front of you,
口説いて見せろよ
go and win her over.
ラキラキ・ラブ・ロクロックラ
Lucky-lucky love, Roku-roku-ra
お茶を濁してちゃ満足できない
Can't be satisfied with just beating around the bush.
次々に運ばれるスロートコードは
The throat chords being delivered one after another
安心、安泰、プレッシャーでいっぱい
are safe and sound, but full of pressure.
きっと君の若さじゃ駆けつける声が出ません
In your youth, I'm sure your voice won't reach.
は？
Huh?
はぁ…
Haa...
ロキロキのロックンロール・ベイビー
Roki-Roki's rockin' roll, baby
ベイビー
Baby
死ぬんじゃねぇぞ お互いになぁ
Don't you go dying now, for both of our sakes.
ラキラキ・ラブ・ロクロックラ
Lucky-lucky love, Roku-roku-ra
叩き鳴らせエレクトリックギターは
Strum that electric guitar
ダンスダンス！
Dance, dance!
さぁ君のすべてを
Now, go and reveal
さらけ出して見せろよ
every single part of yourself.
ラキラキ・ラブ・ロクロックラ
Lucky-lucky love, Roku-roku-ra
ラキラキ・ラブ
Lucky-lucky love
ロクロックラ・ウォー
Roku-roku-ra, woah
死ぬんじゃねぇぞ
Don't you go dying now.
死にたかねぇのはお互い様
Neither of us wants to die.
みんな、4期生5周年記念ライブ見てくれてありがとう！
Everyone, thank you for watching the 4th Gen 5th Anniversary Live!
最後に5周年の記念グッズのお知らせです！
Finally, we have an announcement about the 5th-anniversary commemorative goods!
今回は四季をテーマにしたグッズになっています！
This time, the goods are themed after the four seasons!
既にイラストがいい感じ！
The illustrations already look great!
ということで、それでは一つずつ見ていきましょう！
So, let's take a look at them one by one!
まずは、こちら！アクリルジオラマスタンド（全4種）！
First up is this! Acrylic Diorama Stand (4 types total)!
背景付きのアクリルジオラマなので、迫力満点！
Since it's an acrylic diorama with a background, it's very impactful!
春夏秋冬で繋がるイラストなので、
The illustrations connect across the four seasons,
4期生みんな並べて飾っちゃお！よろしくお願いします！
so line up all the 4th Gen members and display them! Please look forward to it!
さぁ、次のグッズは、ルーナ！
Alright, the next item is from Luna!
はーい！
Okay!
次のグッズは、こちらなななー！ででーん！
The next item is this, nanana! Ta-dah!
ランダム缶バッジなななー！
Random Can Badges, nanana!
全部で8種類の中から、ランダムで1種類入っています！
There are 8 types in total, and you get one at random!
アンダーホログラムという仕様で、
They feature an 'under-hologram' design,
名前の部分がキラッと光る仕様らしいのなー！
where the name part apparently sparkles and shines!
そして、今回、わための衣装は、とっても清楚で可愛らしい、
And this time, Watame's outfit is so neat and lovely,
まさに春！って感じなので、
it really feels like spring!
ぜひぜひみんな手に入れてななー！
So please, everyone, make sure to get one!
次は、わためちゃん、よろしくななー！
Next up is Watame-chan, over to you!
はい！ではでは、お次はスマホショルダーバッグです！
Yes! Now then, next is the Smartphone Shoulder Bag!
春夏秋冬問わず使えるスポーティーなスマホショルダーは、
This sporty smartphone shoulder bag can be used in any season.
透明窓付きなのでお気に入りのグッズを見せることができます！
It has a transparent window to show off your favorite goods!
アクスタや缶バッジを収納して、推しアピールしちゃいましょう！お次はトワっち！
Store your acrylic stands and badges to show off your fave! Next up, Towatchi!
はい！わためから引き継ぎました、こんやっぴー！
Yes! Taking over from Watame, Kon-yappi!
次は、こちら！マルチケース！イェーイ！
Next is this! Multi-case! Yay!
イヤホンや缶バッジを入れて、バッグに付けて、推しと一緒にお出かけ気分に！
Put your earphones or badges in it, attach it to your bag, and feel like you're out with your fave!
ということで、トワ達を入れて、色んな所に出かけて写真をポストしてね！
So, put Towa and the others inside, go to various places, and post photos!
そして、最後はこちら！ドトーン！ブロマイドケース！
And finally, this! Ta-dah! Bromide Case!
なんと！みんなの複製手書きメッセージ入りです！
What's more, it contains printed handwritten messages from everyone!
アルバムのような形で、コレクション性のあるグッズとなっております！
It's shaped like an album, making it a highly collectible item!
ということで、どうでしたか？
So, what did you think?
どのグッズも素敵だったと思いませんか？
Don't you think all the goods were wonderful?
ということで、皆さん、是非買ってください！
With that, everyone, please do buy them!
購入については、概要欄のリンクやXをチェックしてみてください！
Regarding purchases, please check the link in the description or X!
ではでは、皆さん、次の配信でお会いしましょう！
Well then, everyone, see you in the next stream!
以上、4期生からでした！バイバーイ！
That's all from the 4th Generation! Bye-bye!
1day 4colors